Do you remember
你觉得
the words you told me this afternoon,
今天下午你跟我说
lady will do makeup for someone who loves her.
悦己者容
Is that common?
算不算常态啊
It depends
那要看
on how you define the relationship of you two.
你怎么定义你俩的关系
Based on my experience,
以我的经验来看
girls are always right.
女生永远是对的
If you want to ask her out,
你要想追她
then you have to admit mistakes.
那就得认
I don't say that I want to ask her on date.
谁说要追她了
En?
嗯
Well, I do have a good feeling on her.
我对她是有点好感
Just good feeling?
好感
I have a crush on Mu Xiaoyu!
我就喜欢牧小鱼
What?!
你说什么
I...
我
I said, I have a crush on Mu Xiaoyu!
我说我喜欢牧小鱼
I knew it!
我就知道
When did it happen?
什么时候的
I have no idea.
我也不清楚
It just happened.
就顺其自然吧
Maybe...
可能
I just had good feeling on Mu Xiaoyu.
就对牧小鱼有好感了
What?!
什么
What did you just say?
你说什么
I said,
我说
I love Mu Xiaoyu.
我说我喜欢牧小鱼
Wow!
哎呀
I have been waiting this news for a whole year!
我磕了一年的糖
My little brother finally grow up!
我儿子终于长大了
So does Xiaoyu know about this?
那小鱼知道吗
You guys also saw the situation this afternoon,
今天下午你们也看见了
this girl maybe
这姑娘可能
has some problems on
在感情方面
her feeling.
有一些什么障碍
Quite so.
小鱼确实
That's exactly her.
小鱼就这样
But, never mind,
不过 没事
I will help you.
姐们帮你
Help him what?
你帮他干什么
For god's sake,
我天爷呀
can you guys don't show up together?
你们能不能一块出现
I said I like Mu...
我说我喜欢 牧
What are you talking about?
你们在说什么
I...
我
I...I said I like...
我 我说我喜欢
like...
喜欢
What do you like?
你喜欢什么
Tripe.
涮肚
I like eating tripe.
我喜欢涮肚
Come on!
走开你
You are surely not talking about this.
你肯定不是说这个吧
Why they have these expressions?
他们三个都什么脸
Tell me.
你说说
Nothing, never mind.
没事 没事 没事
Let's eat!
吃饭 吃饭 吃饭
Let's eat, Xiaoyu.
吃饭小鱼
You guys spoke ill of me, don't you?
你们说我坏话了是不是
It tastes nice!
真好吃
Hey,
哎
look,
你们说
Will I look nice
我化妆
if I put on makeup?
应该也挺好看的吧
Let's try.
试试呗
You two have pretty face anyway,
反正你们俩底子都好
you will look perfect.
肯定好看
I think so.
我觉得也是
I finish.
我吃完了
Great!
太好了 太好了
There is still smell, Sis Hao.
还有味 小好姐
What a pity,
只可惜呀
like Nan Bei said,
就像南北说的
Although I put on makeup,
我就算化了妆
nobody appreciate.
也没有悦己者
That words don't sound like a feminist said.
你这话有点不女权了啊
Putting on makeup or not,
化不化妆
we do it for ourselves.
那是给自己看的
You have watched this video for a thousand times,
你这片看了八百遍了
you still watch it?
还看呢
No matter how many times,
就算看再多遍
this part
这个片段
still moves me a lot.
还是会让我很感动啊
Look,
哎
I say,
要我说啊
best friends become lovers,
从最好的朋友变成情侣
which is unreal.
那是真不靠谱
Personally,
我个人看法
somebody
有些人
are afraid of losing friends,
因为害怕失去友情
so
所以
they hesitate to express their feeling.
在爱情面前停滞不前
Somebody
有些人
enjoy the feeling of dating with girls
他就享受那种恋人未满
in romantic air,
夹杂着那种暧昧气氛
pretending a naive boy to the end.
执意装傻到底
Actually,
但事实上
one chases love,
拥有爱情
perhaps he won't lose friendship.
它不一定就会失去友情
Nietzsche said,
尼采曾经说过
It is not a lack of love,
最坏的婚姻
but a lack of friendship
不是缺少爱情
that makes unhappy marriages.
而是缺少友情
So love and friendship
所以说爱情和友情
can coexist.
是共存的
Even sometimes,
甚至于有时候
love and friendship
爱情和友情
can be better when they coexist.
共存的感情会更好
Xiong Zishi,
熊子时
you barely read books,
你这么没文化一个人
how can you
什么时候
say so philosophical words?
能说出这么有哲理的话
I...
我
I am a bluffer of love.
我可是爱情口嗨选手嘛
So,
所以说
putting on makeup,
化妆这个事
give it a try?
你要不要再考虑一下
Well?
试试看
I don't know how to use this,
我不会用这
how much shall I use?
这抹多少
Too much...
太多了 太多了
Do you know how to use this, Sis Hao?
小好姐 你会吗
I learn how to use it
我也是
from a teaching video for a long time.
自己跟视频学了好久
We have makeup club in our college,
但是我们学校有化妆社
how about you go to join it?
你们要不要去看看
They will teach you some easy makeups.
她们会教一些速成的妆
Speaking of which,
对了
they will hold an activity tomorrow morning.
她们明天早上就有活动
Great, Xioayu!
可以呀 小鱼
We can go together,
我们明天一起去
maybe,
说不定
you can impress someone.
你就可以惊艳到某人呢
Huh...
切
There are really so many girls
还真有这么多女生
wasting their time here!
在这儿浪费时间啊
Shut up, come on.
别嘴硬了 进来吧
Hello,
同学
excuse me,
打扰一下
may I ask
我问一下
who will give the class?
一会儿谁给我们上课
Our club chief.
社长啊
You two must be new here.
你们两个新来的吧
Our chief is so great,
我们社长可厉害了
she is a famous beauty blogger
是知名的仿妆博主
who has over two million fans!
全网两百多万粉丝呢
Ok, thank you.
好 谢谢
It is worthy of coming!
赚了 赚了
Luckily we borrow staff from Sis Hao.
幸亏找小好姐借了物资
Two million fans...
两百多万
so this chief doesn't do other things?
平时啥也不干的吗
En?
哎
Oi...
哎哎哎
Giving up before start,
还没开始就放弃
it's just so you.
果然是你的处事风格
Clam down...
冷静 冷静
Ok,
好了
Let's begin
今天我们要来开始
our class.
今天的课程
Qin, come here.
小秦 上来一下
Today,
今天呢
we will teach you
我们要来教大家
how to make
如何打造一款
eyebrows fitting yourselves.
适合自己的眉形
Before this,
在此之前呢
we shall do a review
我们先来复习一下
on the last class,
上节课的内容
which is how to make matte finish.
化一个雾面底妆
First, we need to choose
首先我们要选择一个
a foundation one shade
比自己肤色
lighter than our skin tone,
浅一号的粉底液
spurt evenly on your face.
均匀地点在脸上
Then use this
然后再用这种
half-wet sponge
半湿的海绵
rolling spread.
转动式涂抹
After that,
完成之后呢
we use powder to finish the makeup,
最后我们要用散粉定妆
put it on our skin gently.
轻轻地压在皮肤上
Well, next,
好 接下来
we will learn how to pencil our eyebrows.
好 我们来学习画眉毛
Our eyebrows are second important
眉毛在整个妆容中
during the whole makeup
的作用呢
following eye makeup.
仅次于眼妆
A good camber
一个好的眉形
can also
还能够达到
modify the shape of face,
修饰脸型的作用
including round face.
包括圆脸
Me?
我
First of all,
首先呢
We need to take
我们需要拿出我们的
our eyebrow shaver out
刮眉刀
to shave
我们要刮掉
our surplus hair
自己眉毛旁边
beside our eyebrow.
多余的杂毛
Look where the top of eyebrow is,
注意眉峰的位置
maintain its original shape.
尽量保留它原有的形状
Everyone, let's try.
大家可以都动手试一下
Ask me when there are questions.
有什么问题再问我
If it's your first time,
如果是第一次修眉毛
you can use tweezers
可以使用镊子
in case you make mistakes.
这样不太容易出错
May I help you?
我来帮你吧
You are not that warmhearted.
你有那么好
If you make yourself look like a monster,
你要是化成鬼一样
and people see you,
出去呢
my reputation will be ruined.
我的声誉也不保
I just want to be judged by your mistakes.
我只是不想被你连累
Uh!!!
啊
You did this on purpose!
你故意的吧你
You are twenties,
二十来岁的人
but never shave your eyebrows,
连眉毛都没怎么修过
how you can live on without this?
你活得该有多粗糙
Who said that I never shave my eyebrows?
谁说我没有修过眉毛
I am just too busy
我哪有那些闲工夫
for serious matters.
我一堆正经事要干呢我
You are also not doing well in
你的正事
your serious matters.
忙得也不怎么样嘛
Well,
好 今天呢
so much for today,
我们课程就到这儿
you can use mirror
大家可以打开镜子
to find out which eyebrow shape
看一下今天学习到的
fits you perfectly.
属于适合自己的眉形
Why are you laughing?
你笑什么
Are you making fun of me?
你是不是笑话我
A teacher makes fun of student?
你一个老师笑话学生啊
Xiaoyu, easy...
小鱼 小鱼
How dare you make fun of me?
你笑话我是不是
Why you stop me?!
你拦着我干嘛
Easy, easy.
好了 好了
One with great power cannot defeat a local villain.
强龙斗不过地蛇
How about
走走走
have a rest and take a meal?
吃顿饭休息一会儿
Xiaoyu.
小鱼
Let's eat together?
一块吃饭呗
We had taken our meal,
我们吃过饭了
sorry.
就不一起吃了吧
Really?
真的吗
Yep,
吃过了
Then why are you
但你为什么老是
showing your back to me?
背对着我
I am not.
我没有
Are you feeling bad with your eyes?
你怎么了 眼睛不舒服
My eyes are...
我眼睛 我眼
fine.
眼睛没事啊
Look.
看
Why are you blocking your eyebrows?
为啥一直挡着自己眉毛
I'm not.
我没有
Why I block my eyebrows?
怎么会挡着自己眉毛呢
I just wanna
我就是想
take a good picture
天气好 拍个
in this beautiful day.
大片什么的
Such a nice day!
天气真好
Uh!
哎呀
Ah!
天气真好啊
Take a posture first.
先给你比个姿势
I am fine,
真没事
really.
没事 没事
So you don't need to go to see a doctor?
不用去医院
Definitely not.
不用 不用 不用
Let me see, what's wrong?
我看看 怎么了
No, thanks.
不必了
Let me see.
我看看
Let me see...
我看
No!
不用
I turn my words back,
我收回之前那句话
natural beauty fits you.
你还是自然美最好
You can learn from me!
你们想学化妆找我呀
I am a beauty guru.
我是美妆博主
So are you?
你也是美妆博主
Yep.
嗯
You don't know?
你们不知道啊
Here,
来
let me show my account.
我给你们看看我的账号
Only 500 followers?
你才五百粉丝
Even I have more.
我粉丝都比你多
I, am not good at
我这个人
doing homework,
题做不对
or study,
这个书也看不懂
so I just find a hobby
我这不给自己
for myself,
找个爱好吗
besides,
而且
they are my die-hard fans.
我这个真的都是铁粉
Let me teach you two?
要不我教你们俩
I don't wanna study,
我要不想学习了
nor learn to put on makeup.
我也不想学化妆
No!
别呀
Xiaoyu, you have such a pretty face,
小鱼 你底子那么好
you will look so nice after doing makeup.
化完妆肯定好看
No,
不
I am so happy that I don't put on makeup.
我不容最悦己
Wrong, Xiaoyu.
不行 小鱼
Think about it,
你想想啊
You can't let Yin Nan look down on you.
咱不能让殷楠看扁啊
Right?
是不是
In her eyes, you,
你现在在她眼里吧
both of us
我们俩现在在她眼里
are just two
就是那个两个
college students lacking taste in life.
缺乏生活品味的大学生
Can you bear it?
你能忍吗
No!
忍不了
That's right.
这就对了
Qing, please teach us!
小晴 教我们
Teach us some quick skills.
教我们速成的
No problem.
没问题
Actually, wearing makeup is much easier
其实化妆比学习
than study.
简单多了
You two can use
你们俩先抹点
some skin cares to moisturizer your skin.
护肤品做下保湿
I fetch you some samples.
我给你们拿点试用装
Use skin care first
先 先抹化妆品
to moisturizer your skin.
保湿
Here,
来
here you are.
这个给你
This, you can use this.
这个 这个给你用
Fanfan, you use one?
凡凡 你也用一个
No, thank you.
我就不用了
Before I become a doctor,
在考上博士之前
I don't wanna waste my time on
我没有打算在化妆上
wearing makeup.
浪费自己的时间
How is it wasting your time?
这怎么是浪费时间呢
When I don't put on makeup,
我不化妆的时候
I feel I am common,
我觉得自己挺普通的
but after I wear makeup,
但是我化完妆
I feel like that
我觉得
I look like a film star.
我长得有点像哪个明星
Wearing makeup has a hypnotic effect.
化妆会产生催眠效果
This confidence,
这种自信
will fade with cleansing.
会随着卸妆一同消失的
So you would better read more books.
你还不如多看点书
What you are holding?
你手里拿这个是什么
This is a foreign exchange event,
这是一个涉外交流活动
which Mr. Li asked me to
李主任让我代表
give a speech on behalf of our grade.
年级上台演讲
Good, then.
好事 这是
Oh,
对了
I send you a video about
我这儿给你们发了一个
how to put on makeup.
化妆的视频
You two can check it up.
你们俩查收一下
Ok!
好嘞 好嘞
Got it!
收到 收到
Dear leaders,
尊敬的各位领导
teachers and students,
老师 同学们
good morning!
大家好
I am Ji Fanxi,
我是来自
a student from
东州财经大学的同学
Dongzhou University of Finance and Economics.
纪凡曦
how is it going?
准备得怎么样了
Don't worry, Mr. Li,
李主任 放心
I am well-prepared.
我都准备好了
Relax,
不用紧张
just share your study
就是跟大一的新生啊
in our
分享一下这个
university
大学里面的
with freshman.
这个学习生活
You shall look energetic then.
到时候搞得精神一点
Energetic?
精神
Yes, just wear little makeup, and dress up.
就是化个妆 打扮一下
Is there any problem?
有什么问题吗
No, no.
没 没
So I have to put on makeup?
就 就必须得化妆吗
Just a light makeup
就是化个淡妆
to make people feel you
感觉人特别特别的
are very energetic,
有精神 饱满
full of power.
状态 状态
Energetic...
精神
Two years in college fly away,
匆匆两年大学时光
looking back on the year I entered this college,
回首起当年新生入校
the most important thing is
最重要的
to find a goal
就是大学四年里
during our four years of college life.
找到一个奋斗的目标
As you can see,
其实已经看到了
I have multiple identities.
那么多的代名词
Well,
那么其实呢
actually,
我其实
after I diverted to
在做模特
model,
转行之后
it has been two years that
已经有两年的时间
I don't make money as a model.
没有再用模特赚过钱
Hey, why Xiaoyu
你说小鱼
puts on makeup suddenly?
怎么就突然化妆了呢
Oh?
哟
Are you showing off?
跟我臭显摆呢
No, no, no...
没有 没有 没有
I'm just confused.
请教请教
Can't you see?
你是真看不出来吗
But,
主要是
she resisted this last day,
她昨天还一直抗拒呢
why she changes her mind today?
怎么今天突然就变了
She does it for you.
化给你看的呗
Really?
化给我看的
Well...
那
If you say so,
照你这么说
she does have a feeling about me?
她对我还有点意思
Then why she is so bashful?
那她干嘛扭扭捏捏的
You just don't have experience in love.
你是真没恋爱经验
You two are good mates,
你们俩现在是兄弟
good friends.
是红颜 是知己
Once something goes wrong,
万一这步跨错了
you two even can't be friends anymore,
朋友都做不了
not to mention debate match.
还怎么打比赛
If something goes wrong,
跨错了
I will try my best to
我就想尽办法
maintain our friendship.
回到兄弟的位置啊
Nothing to be afraid.
这有什么好怕的
You can do that.
你是有这觉悟
But Xiaoyu maybe doesn't have this confidence.
那人家可没这信心
Then I can make her have one,
那我让她有这信心
problem solved.
不就行了
Fine.
行啊
Hey, bro!
哎 同学
Your posture is wrong,
你这姿势不太对
let me help you.
我来帮你调整一下
Yong lady,
小姑娘
this makeup suits you so much.
这个妆真的太适合你了
Sister,
姐姐
this is a nice makeup,
这个妆是挺好看的
but,
但是
can you put it on my whole face?
能不能给我化整张脸
We only do half face for trying out.
我们试妆就是化半张脸
If you wanna buy our makeup,
你如果要买的话
I will make up your whole face.
我再给您化个全妆吧
The price is...
价格是
Then I shall cleanse it.
那还是卸掉吧
Then I recommend you
那我给你推荐
our latest cleansing,
我们最新款的卸妆水
which takes...
这款的价格是
cleanse it.
卸掉吧
Alas...
哎
So,
所以
what we will train today is...
今天的训练内容是
There is no game to prepare for.
没有什么比赛需要准备
The basic training is finished.
基础训练做得差不多了
And atmospheric pressure is also relatively low.
气压也比较低
And it's bad weather.
天气也不怎么好
Alas...
哎
So let's go?
散了吧
Ok.
散了呗
Ok, I will go to sleep.
散了 回去洗洗睡吧
Stop! What's going on?
干嘛呀 干嘛呀 干嘛呀
What's wrong with you guys?
大家这是怎么了
If you have this attitude,
同志们要是这个状态
how can I face
让我怎么向
our old coach
刚刚站起来的
who can just stand up?
老教练交代呀
Right, Hao?
是不是 小好
Yep.
嗯
How about
那要不
starting an inside debate now!
我们来场队内赛吧
The topic...
辩题
is that...
辩题就是
lady will wear makeup for someone who loves her,
女为悦己者容
or for herself.
女为己容
I believe for someone who loves her.
我站悦己者
Great! I disagree.
巧了 我站反方
Then...I agree with him.
那 那我也站悦己者
You boys
你们男生
just evolve too slowly!
真的是进化太慢了
Then I shall use truth
那我就用真理来
to give you a lesson,
教育教育你们
ok?
好吧
Yes, please!
你快教育教育我吧
How to punish the loser?
输了的人怎么着
How about livestream putting on makeup on TikTok?
上抖音直播化妆好吧
Good.
好啊
I will give you a thumbs up then.
到时候我给你们点赞啊
We will see!
谁怕你哟
I have best debater!
我们这儿有最佳辩手
Ok?
好吧
I..didn't say I'm in...
我 我没有说我要上啊
Bro...
兄弟
Let's begin!
来呀
Ok!
来啊
Great!
很好
I like your
就是喜欢你们这种
energy.
干劲
Finished.
好
Look,
你看
I said,
我就说
I am a real
我是个正儿八经的
beauty blogger.
美妆博主吧
Look how beautiful you two are!
你们俩现在多好看呀
Look great, Qing.
不错呀 小晴
I can't make the decision.
我有点挑不出来了
These three lipsticks,
这三个口红
which color do you think
你们觉得哪个颜色
fits
比较适合
my clothes?
我今天的衣服
For what?
你要干嘛呀
Nan Bei said he
南北说
will help a guy from Department of Astronomy.
要帮天文系哥们一个忙
They will take photos of starry sky,
晚上那个要去拍星空
so he asked me to go with him.
叫我一块去
Romantic!
挺浪漫啊
Is he asking you to go out with him?
他是不是要找你约会呀
Nonsense!
约什么会呀
He just can't handle this himself
他就是一个人搞不定
so he asked me to help him.
叫我去帮忙的
How about first one, the crimson one?
第一个 那个深红色呢
This one?
这个吗
Will it be too red?
会不会太凶了呀
I gave it a try,
我刚才试了一下
see.
你看
Then the pink one in the middle?
那中间那个粉色呢
I have a comparison,
这个我刚才也比了一下
this pink,
这死亡芭比粉
won't it reflect light at night?
到晚上不会反光吧
Look.
你看
You really go to help him???
你这是帮忙呢
What?
怎么
Don't tell me
你不会是
you agree with the con side.
认同他们持方了吧
I don't.
我才没有
I just provide
我这是为了我方提供
strong evidence for us.
强有力的证据
I just
我这是 我
go to gather some information.
我刺探军情去了
I heard that
听说
Nan Bei likes grapefruit color.
南北好像喜欢西柚色
Then I will take this one,
我正好就选这支了
I also think that this color is nice.
我也觉得这挺好看的
I will use this.
要不就涂这个吧
Can you handle this?
你会不会弄啊
Why this
不知道为什么
tripod just can't
这三脚架怎么就
be fixed?
固定不住呢
Look at me,
你看我
what's different today?
今天有没有什么不一样
You bought new clothes?
你买了身新衣服
I have worn this for whole semester!
我这衣服穿一个学期了
Look closer.
你再好好看看
What?
怎么了
I used a grapefruit color lipstick.
我换了个西柚色的口红
Does it look good?
好看吗
Do...do you wanna drink milky tea?
你 你喝奶茶吗
I...I go to buy you one...
我 我去给你买杯奶茶去
I'm asking you question!
我问你好不好看
Why are you leaving?
你走了干嘛呀
Beautiful!
好漂亮
Yep.
嗯
What are you looking at?
你看什么
I...
我
I believe that you are cold.
我看你冷了
I'm not.
我不冷
You are.
你冷
You must be cold.
你 你得冷
I'm not,
我不冷
Just wear this.
你就穿着吧
What are you doing?
干什么呢
Watching makeup teaching video.
化妆视频
You watch this every day.
你不天天看吗
It's Fanfan's computer,
凡凡的
she forgot to shut it down.
她忘记关电脑了
And more,
还有 还有
this also belongs to Fanfan.
这个 也是凡凡的
She begins to put on makeup?
凡凡开始化妆了
There is more,
还有 还有
This is also hers.
这个也是凡凡的
She doesn't wear high heels.
凡凡不穿高跟鞋啊
Maybe she...
难道她
No way,
不可能
she said that
她自己说过
she will never date with someone until being a doctor.
考博之前不谈恋爱的
A friend from student union
今天学生会的同学
told me a thing
跟我说了件事
which can explain these.
可能跟这个有关
What are you doing?
你们干嘛呀
We wanna help you
我们想要帮你
put on makeup.
化妆
For what?
为什么
I never do makeup.
我不用化妆的
You will deliver a speech,
一会儿演讲
of course, you need to look nice.
当然要精神点
How do you know about this?
你们怎么知道
I...
我
Don't hesitate,
别我我我了
we know the whole thing.
我们都知道了
This is heel band-aid,
这个 后跟贴
It's your first time to wear high heels,
你第一次穿高跟鞋
your feet will swell without this.
不贴脚肯定会肿的
Here you are.
给
Thank you, guys.
谢谢你们
Never mind, we are sisters.
别客气 自家姐们
Come on, sisters,
来吧 姐妹们
Let's do this!
上
Wait a minute!
等 等一下
I...I am nervous...
我 我有点紧张
Don't worry,
放心
close your eyes,
闭上眼睛
we will finish in minutes.
很快就会过去的
Well...
哎哎哎
Look,
怎么样
is it good?
不错吧
Beautiful girls, handsome boys,
姑娘漂亮 小伙帅
in a good atmosphere.
很有气氛吧
The losers' faces
一会儿谁要是输了
with makeup
我就把他带妆的脸
will be put on the board.
画上去
But this team game,
但是这次队内赛
you can't act like last time,
你们可不能像上次似的
you need to maintain the principle of
还是要秉承着友谊第一
friendship first, competition second,
比赛第二的态度
Is that clear?
知道吗
- Uh...- En?!!!
啊 嗯
We are ready.
开始吧
Good.
好
Well,
好的
great thank to
非常感谢
President Zhang and Dean Wang
张校长跟王院长
for their speech on
给音乐节带来的
music Festival.
精彩致辞
The next,
接下来呢
welcome the outstanding student representative
有请东州财经大学
from DUFE,
优秀学生代表
Ji Fanxi
纪凡曦
who will give us a speech with
给我们带来主题为
the topic of memories.
回忆狂想的发言
Welcome.
有请
Dear leaders,
尊敬的各位领导
teachers, and students,
老师 同学们
good morning!
大家好
I am Ji Fanxi,
我是来自
a student,
东州财经大学的学生
from DUFE.
纪凡曦
I am so delighted to
非常高兴
meet with everyone.
今天与大家见面
I...
我
regret to announce
遗憾地宣布
the result of this game:
这次比赛的结果
the winner is
获胜的是
pro side, Xiaoyu team.
对方辩友小鱼队
The makeups
化妆品
are ready.
我都已经准备好了
We are waiting for your livestream on TikTok.
就等着你们抖音直播了
I suddenly remember that I shall go for a class...
我突然想起来我有节课
Students are waiting...
同学们等着我
Stop.
站住
You have no class at all this week.
你这周一节课都没有
Your job of student union
你学生会的工作
was all rearranged by me.
我全部安排出去了
So you three
所以你们三个
just sit down
就老老实实
and livestream here.
在这儿直播吧
So the sooner, the better.
那事不宜迟
Wait,
等会儿
I wanna say a word,
我还有一句话要说
well...
那个
if you don't wannna
你要是
wear makeup, then don't.
不想化妆就别化了
Because you are beautiful
因为你不化妆
without any makeup.
也很美
Well...
天哪
You can't escape.
你逃不掉的
Come here.
过来
The Earth has six billion people,
地球上有六十亿人
one can meet a thousand people a day,
一天会遇到一千人
and 365 thousand people
一年会遇到三十六万
in a year,
五千人
29.2million people
一生会遇见两千九百
in his life.
二十万人
So the probability of
相遇的概率
meeting is
是百分之零点零零
We meet so much people in our life,
一生相识这么多人
but the probability of falling in love is pretty low.
相爱的概率如此之低
You take film elective course,
你上电影选修课
why have I accompany you?
让我陪你来干嘛
Just for watching movie?
陪你看电影啊
Last week I came to class,
我上周来上课的时候
I found he also takes this course.
发现他也选了这门课
Everyone,
同学们
don't be disappointed,
不要太失望
Although the probability
虽然相爱的概率
is low,
如此之低
have you found out that
但是你有没有发现
there are many
在我们身边
lovers or couples
还是有很多的
around us.
夫妻和情侣
And why is that?
这是为什么呢
Because
因为呀
long long ago,
在很久很久以前
a great great invention
有一项非常伟大的发现
solved this problem
解决了相爱的难题
which is this.
就是这个
It sounds like a pyramid scheme.
怎么跟搞传销的似的
Does she have an
她家不会有
apple orchard?
一片苹果地吧
The next words she gonna say may be
接下来是不是说
apple is a panacea.
苹果包治百病啊
In some ancient myths,
在有些古代神话中
we human
我们人类
have experienced love
正是通过一个苹果
between man and woman
才领悟了
through an apple.
男女之间的爱情
So,
所以
if you receive an apple
如果在跨年夜的时候
from a boy
你收到了
in the eve of the new year,
异性送给你的苹果
guess what,
那注意了
this doesn't mean good luck,
不是在祝你平安
but wanna date with you.
而是在向你求爱
Date...
求爱
Understand?
懂了吗
Today is a festival,
这么凑热闹的日子
but you are still so quiet.
你这么消停
I have grown up,
我已经成长了
realizing there are more serious things
认识到这个世界上
in this world,
除了肤浅的爱情
except dating.
还是有很多深刻的事
Have I mentioned date?
我提爱情了吗
We are sisters for years,
这么多年姐们
I know what you gonna say
你一张嘴
before you say.
我就知道你要说什么
Hello, give you an apple.
你好 送你一个苹果
Wow! You!
哎哟妈呀 你呀
It's wasting my apple.
别浪费我苹果
What are you talking about?
你什么意思啊
Wait,
不是
what are you doing?
你这干什么呢
Uh...
真是
My God!
我的天哪
You look nice,
你长得也挺帅
but please don't do
能不能不要
this nasty thing!
干这么龌龊的事情啊
You don't get it,
你不懂
it's a present for girls.
这是给广大女生发福利
Have you asked
你问过
our opinion?
广大女生意见吗你
Do you know why girls
你知道为什么广大女生
don't wanna fall in love?
不爱谈恋爱吗
Because we don't wanna
就是因为
date with someone like you!
怕碰到你这种人
Show love to every girl.
普遍撒网
We can watch movies,
电影不好看吗
play games,
游戏不好玩吗
enjoy desert,
甜品不好吃吗
we will never spend time
花时间在你这种
on an asshole like you.
渣男身上
I...
不是我
Good!
说得好
Uh...
不是
I...
我就
Our college is
你说咱们学校
a national key university.
好歹也是个九八五
But the thoughts of boys
这男生想法
are too shaky.
怎么这么不靠谱
Is it related to
男生靠谱不靠谱
their records?
跟成绩有关系吗
Just like human,
跟人一样
it is gender difference.
是性别关系好不好
Not all, right?
不全是了 对吧
What do you mean?
什么意思啊
I do a divination for you,
我给你算了一下
Your love fortune is good this week.
你这周的恋爱运势不错
A boy who has had a crush on you
会有一个暗恋你
for long time
很久的人
will profess his love for you.
跟你告白
Come on, witch Xiong.
行了 熊大仙
This is feudal superstitious,
你别搞这些封建迷信了
ok?
好不好
If you have time,
有这个时间
you shall think about our debate.
你能不能搞搞辩论词
You are not interested,
你要是没兴趣
then I won't speak.
我就不说喽
You don't say, then I want to know.
你不说我偏要听
I won't say!
我就不说
Say!
说
No!
不说
Please tell me.
你快说嘛
Well,
哎呀
look,
喏
that's him.
就是他喽
Though Nan Bei
虽然南北这个人吧
is not tall or handsome,
不高不帅
and annoying,
又作又烦的
compared with that asshole,
但是跟渣男之间比起来
he is much better.
还是相差一百个蛋蛋
You shall wait and see!
你就等着被告白吧
But he sometime is
可是他有时候就是
unmanly.
娘们叽叽的
You can shut up,
别嘴硬了啊
and wait.
你就等着
You can laugh out.
想笑就笑吧
Look,
快看
everything goes fine...
没事 没事 没事 没事
Look, Xiaoyu,
我跟你说 小鱼
He is hiding his feeling...
这就是先抑后扬
Nonsense!
先抑后扬个鬼
Go back to train!
回去训练
Let's go.
走
Xiaoyu.
小鱼
What's wrong with her?
她怎么了
Nothing.
没事
I told you,
我说的吧
he is hiding feeling.
先抑后扬
It must be from Nan Bei.
肯定是南北送的
Dango,
团子
here you are.
你的
Sis Hao,
小好姐
these apples are yours?
都是你的
Yep.
对呀
Everyone can have an apple
正好每个人能吃一点
for vitamin supplement.
补充维生素
Do you do wholesale now?
你是转战批发了吗
I didn't buy these,
这个不是我买的
don't know what's going on today,
今天不知道怎么回事
many junior male schoolmates gave me apples.
好多学弟都送了我苹果
There are animal plagues recently,
最近动物瘟疫
unstoppable spreading,
像龙卷风一样
I suggest you don't eat it.
我建议你们还是别吃了
Are they
这两者之间
relevant?
有什么联系啊
Of course.
有啊
Siberian cold rages,
西伯利亚寒流肆虐
taking plagues to
它把瘟疫
west apple plain,
吹到了西苹果平原上
the biggest apple
全世界最大的
producer in the world.
苹果生产商
Almost all apples
这个季节
in this season
几乎所有的苹果
are from there,
都打那儿来
so don't eat it.
还是别吃了
Sounds like unreal.
听着怎么不像真的呢
It's washed, eat it.
吃吧 洗过了
Nan Bei,
南北
do you know,
你知道
the meaning of
今天送苹果的意思
giving apples today?
是什么吗
Yes,
知道啊
wish you are safe.
平安
My children,
孩儿们
happy New Year!
跨年快乐
Why you have so many apples?
你哪儿来这么多苹果
school staff benefits.
校工福利呀
I can't move it
反正我是没有劲
back anyway.
再搬回去了
Then,
一会儿
we will divide these,
咱们就把它给分掉
how are you preparing?
你们准备得怎么样了
I am waiting to give
我可等着跟
update to our coach.
教练汇报情况呢
Do you read newspaper today?
你们今天看报纸了吗
That luck fortune shows
那个运势说
that today is not good for study.
今天不适合搬砖学习
Being lazy
你这个懒
can have a reason?
偷得倒是别致啊
Fine,
那好吧
what's your plan for the festival?
你们准备怎么过节
Right,
就是啊
it is festival,
好不容易过个节
we surely can't go to dormitory
总不能回宿舍
to sleep.
趴着窝里睡吧
Yep.
嗯
How about going to KTV?
那我们去唱歌
Let's check up...
我看一看有没有
They are all ordered.
位置都订满了
How about hotpot?
那要不我们去吃火锅
Hotpot...
火锅呀
The costs are equal to
一顿火锅能
four or five make-up examination fees.
顶我四五门补考呢
Concert?
演唱会呢
Right,
对了
tonight,
今天晚上
there is Jingfei's concert.
好像有景飞的演唱会
Yes!
对对对
Surely, there are no tickets.
肯定买不到票了
Let's go to see fireworks?
要不我们去看烟花吧
Ok.
可以啊 好呀
That's ok.
这可以
Deal.
那就这么定了
Ok, you can go.
好 那你们去吧
You don't come?
你不去吗
I already have arrangement.
我有安排了
En?
哟
Do what?
干嘛去呀
Work overtime.
加班
Work makes me happy.
工作使我快乐呀
Then we can go to People's Square
那我们去人民广场吧
which has less building surrounded,
那边建筑物少
bigger place,
地方大
and we can shoot off fireworks.
还可以放夜明珠
Then,
那一会儿
we can go to buy it.
咱们一起去买呗
En...
嗯
Nan Bei?
南北
I am not available this afternoon.
我下午有事
You can go,
你们去吧
sorry.
不好意思啊
Now that the night is yet to come ,
既然还没有到晚上
we can
我们就
make good use of our time,
合理地利用一下时间
let's train!
操练起来
What?
干嘛
Ah...
哎哟
There is still one day,
这不还有一天呢嘛
instead of being mad now,
你现在在这儿生气
you should think about
还不如想想晚上
how to make it difficult
他跟你告白的时候
when he professes to you.
你该如何刁难他
How do you know that?
你怎么知道他要告白
Certainly.
当然了
Wise people
明眼人一看
can tell.
就能看出来 好不好
Look,
你想想
the eve night,
跨年夜
with fireworks over whole sky.
又是这个漫天的烟花
Why are you laughing?
笑啥 讨厌
What will you do in a while?
你一会儿干嘛去啊
Go to dormitory.
我回趟寝室
My comic club has activities later,
我那个漫画社还有活动
so I will go there.
我一会儿要过去
Then see ya.
那回见
See ya.
拜拜 拜拜
No apples,
不送苹果就算了
but give me stupid pears?
还送梨
Bro shui,
水哥
I know that
知道
our drinks don't suit you,
我们这儿饮料不适合你
you can bring the fruits to squeeze the juice.
自己拿水果过来榨汁啊
It's for Nan Bei.
给南北儿子的
Even ducks have apples!
鸭子都有苹果
Mengyuan gave ducks apples.
梦圆给的
Hey, what are you doing?
喂 你干嘛呢
I'm busy now,
我现在正忙着呢
I'll call you later.
一会儿打给你
Hey!
哎
Nan Bei!
南北